caltrain.com 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy

Peninsula Corridor Joint Powers Board (“we,” “our,” or “us”), which operates Caltrain, respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this privacy policy ("Policy"). This Policy governs your use of the Caltrain general website, accessible at [www.caltrain.com](http://www.caltrain.com/) (the "Site"), and the website at caltrain.transitsherpa.com (the "Mobile Fare Payment Website"), as well as the Mobile Fare Payment Application ("the App") (the "Mobile Fare Payment Website" and the "App" are further, individually and collectively, referred to as the “Mobile Fare Payment System”) . This Policy discloses our collection of information through any use of the Site and the Mobile Fare Payment System. By accessing or otherwise using the Site or the Mobile Fare Payment System, you acknowledge and consent to our collection and use of information as set forth in this Policy.

This Policy may be amended from time to time; the amended Policy will appear on this page; and dates of amendments will appear at the bottom. Please review this Policy periodically for any changes. 

## Collection and Use of Personal Information for the Site

We collect personal information from you when you choose to use certain features of the Site. You provide this personal information, if at all, on a voluntary basis; and we use this information to implement the features and provide the services or information requested.

For example, the “Contact” page of the Site provides, as one of its options, an online form through which to contact us. That form has blanks through which you are asked to provide the following personal information:

  * Your first and last name
  * Your email address
  * Your phone number 
  * Service used

We use this information for the purposes of soliciting feedback and responding to that feedback, as well as for the general purpose of improving the services that we provide. Caltrain does not share this personal information with third parties, except as otherwise permissible by law. 

Similarly, the “Subscribe” feature of the Site asks you to provide your email address.

We use this information to send you e-mail updates to the page(s) you decide. We reserve the right to send major service change and fare e-mail messages to all subscribers. Users may opt out of further such e-mails at any time. (See Opt Out, below.) 

From time to time, we may implement other features of the Site that may request similar personal information. When such features are offered, we may collect personal information such as the following:

  * Your first and last name
  * Your email address
  * Your phone number
  * The Caltrain stations that you travel to and from
  * A PIN or password assigned to or designated by you.

We use this information to implement these features and provide the requested services.

From time to time, you may be asked to participate in an online survey and share personal information, either directly on the Website or through an online survey platform. You will be notified prior to taking the survey how your information will be used. Any information that you provide will not be shared with third parties, unless stated otherwise in the survey.

## Opt Out For The Site

Users may opt out of receiving e-mail from us through our mailing list. To opt out of our mailing list you can unsubscribe or send us an e-mail to remove your address from the subscribed mailing list. 

## Collection and Use of Personal Information for the Mobile Fare Payment System

We collect personal information from you when you choose to create an account (first and last name, phone number and email address) with and/or purchase tickets through the Mobile Fare Payment System. You provide this information on a voluntary basis; and we use this information to implement the features and provide the services or information requested. 

The personal information gathered from you when you use the Mobile Fare Payment System includes the following:

  * Your first and last name
  * Your email address
  * Your phone number
  * Your ticket type
  * The Caltrain stations that you travel to and from
  * Your payment information

Caltrain uses a consultant to oversee the operations of the Mobile Fare Payment System, which is currently moovel. This consultant collects and uses the personal information described above on our behalf. Further information about the consultant's use of your information is described in the consultant's privacy policy, accessible here: [www.moovel-transit.com/en/privacy-us](http://www.moovel-transit.com/en/privacy-us). In the course of gathering and collecting information, the consultant may use vendors to process payments, such as Braintree and PayPal. Further information about how these payment processing vendors use your information can be found in their respective privacy policies, accessible here: <https://www.braintreepayments.com/legal>; <https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>. If in the future we use a different consultant for overseeing the Mobile Fare Payment System, or other vendors for payment processing, we may share the personal information identified above with that consultant to the extent reasonably necessary. 

## Children

The Site is a general-audience website, and we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, you should not and may not provide any information to us through or on the Site or the App. If you are an adult and find that we have inadvertently collected information from a child, please contact us, and we will work to rectify the situation.

## Security

We have security measures in place intended to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your personal information. 

## International

This Policy is intended to cover the collection of information through the Site from residents of the United States. If you are not a resident of the United States or are visiting our website from outside the United States, and submit any of your personal information through the Site, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored in, or processed in the United States. The data protection and similar laws of the United States may be different than those in other parts of the world.

## Notification of Amendments to Policy

If we amend this Policy, we will post the new Policy on this page or otherwise on the Site or Mobile Fare Payment System.

## Disclaimer

This site contains links to other sites. Caltrain.com is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of these sites.

## Contact Us

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Policy or want to review and request changes to any of your personally identifiable information, please [contact us](http://www.caltrain.com/about/contact.html).

Originally adopted July 1, 2004. Amended Oct. 21, 2004; June 30, 2010, and February 7, 2018. This version of the Policy is effective as of the last-listed date.
